<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ADMISSION AID ASSISTANT</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="nsu_about">North South University (NSU), the first private university in Bangladesh, was established in 1992 by the then
        Foundation for Promotion of Education and Research (FPER), a charitable, non-profit, non-commercial and non-political organization.
        The FPER later was renamed as the NSU Foundation and is presently called The North South Foundation for Education and Research.
        The Foundation is comprised of a group of eminent industrialists, prominent patrons of education, notable philanthropists, widely
        experienced academics and senior civil servants of the country. In the early 1990s, they had a dream to set up a world-class university
        as a center of excellence in higher education in the private sector. Their dedication, tireless efforts, and hard work paved the way for the approval of the establishment of NSU.</string>
    <string name="brac_about">
        BRAC University (BRACU) is a private University in Bangladesh. It was founded as a branch of the BRAC organization by Fazle Hasan Abed in 2001 under the Private University Act, The university 
        ranked 1st among the private universities and 3rd among all the universities in research output on the QS Asian University Ranking 2018 Bangladesh.
    </string>

    <string name="iub_about">
        Independent University, Bangladesh (Bengali: ইন্ডিপেন্ডেন্ট বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়) or IUB is one of the oldest private universities in Bangladesh located in Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka, Bangladesh. It was established in
        1993 by the Private University Act, 1992.[1][2] The business programs are accredited by the US based ACBSP.
</string>

    <string name="ewu_about">
        . East West University was established in 1996 as a non-profit organization. The university is the first major project of the Progoti Foundation for Education and Development (PFED), a non-profit, non-political, charitable organization maintained by a group of academics, business leaders, professionals and education enthusiasts led by Dr. Mohammed Farashuddin, economist and former governor of Bangladesh Bank.
BBA, BSc in Computer Science and BA in English at the previous campus at 45, Mohakhali Commercial Area, Dhaka. The university has some 10,400 students, in its Aftab Nagar Campus, Dhaka.

    </string>

    <string name="aiub_about">
        American International University-Bangladesh (Bengali: আমেরিকান ইন্টারন্যাশনাল ইউনিভার্সিটি-বাংলাদেশ), commonly known as AIUB is an accredited and renowned private university located at Kuratoli Road, Kuril in Dhaka, Bangladesh.[2]
        The university is an independent organization with own Board of Trustees.[3] It offers several degree programs at graduate and undergraduate level from four faculties, particularly in the field of engineering and business studies.

    </string>

    <string name="uap_about">
        University of Asia Pacific (UAP) was established in 1996 as a private university under the Private University Act 1992. Its curriculum has been approved by The University Grants Commission of the
        Government of the People Republic of Bangladesh. The university started its operation in the first semester of classes in 1996, and offered four-year bachelor degree programs in Computer Science
        and Technology and Business Administration only. Now UAP offers undergraduate programs in English, Law, Architecture, Business Administration, Civil Engineering, Computer Science and Engineering, Electrical
        and Electronic Engineering and Pharmacy.
UAP has been sponsored by University of Asia Pacific Foundation, a non-profit, non-commercial organisation based in Dhaka, Bangladesh.

    </string>

    <string name="uiu_about">
        United International University or UIU is a private university located in Dhaka, Bangladesh, The government of Bangladesh approved the establishment of United International University in 2003 under
        the Private University Act (PUA) of 1992 (now replaced by PUA 2010).[1] Financial support came from the United Group, a Bangladeshi business conglomerate.

    </string>

    <string name="northern_about">
        Northern University Bangladesh (Bengali: নর্দান বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়) or NUB is a leading private university in Dhaka, Bangladesh. It was established in 2002. The university was sponsored and founded by International Business Agriculture and Technology (IBAT) Trust.

    </string>
    <string name="seu_about">
        Southeast University (Bengali: সাউথইস্ট বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়) or SEU is a private university in Banani, Dhaka, Bangladesh. The University was established under the Private University Act, 1992 approved by the Government of the People Republic of Bangladesh.[3] Its permanent campus is in 251/A and 252, Tejgaon Industrial Area, Dhaka-1208, Bangladesh. SEU ranked 11th among private universities in Bangla Tribune University Ranking 2017 (Perceptual Ranking)

    </string>

    <string name="du_about">
        The University of Dhaka (Bengali: ঢাকা বিশ্ববিদ্যালয় [ɖʰaka biʃʃobiddalɔe̯], also known as Dhaka University or simply DU) is the oldest university in Bangladesh. The university is ranked number one on the Bangladesh University Ranking 2017.[4] Established in 1921 during the British Raj, it has made significant contributions to the modern history of Bangladesh.[5][6][7][8] After the Partition of India, it became the focal point of progressive and democratic movements in Pakistan. Its students and teachers played a central role in the rise of Bengali nationalism and the independence of Bangladesh.


    </string>

    <string name="ju_about">
        Jagannath University (Bengali: জগন্নাথ বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়) is a government-financed public university[2][3] in Sadarghat, Dhaka, the capital of Bangladesh.[4] Jagannath University is in the southern part of Dhaka city near the River Buriganga.


    </string>

    <string name="jnu_about">
        Jahangirnagar University (Bengali: জাহাঙ্গীরনগর বিশ্ববিদ্যালয় Jahangirnôgôr Bishwôbidyalôy, University Acronym: জাবি or JU) is a public university in Bangladesh, based in Savar Upazila, Dhaka.[2] It is one of the top and only fully residential[3] university in Bangladesh.[2]
The university was established in 1970 by the Jahangirnagar Muslim University Ordinance of the government of Pakistan. Its first vice-chancellor, Mafiz Uddin Ahmad (PhD in chemistry, University of Illinois, Chicago) took up office on 24 September 1970. The first group of students, a total of 150, were enrolled in four departments: Economics, Geography, Mathematics, and Statistics. Its formal inauguration was delayed until 12 January 1971, when the university was launched by Rear Admiral S. M. Ahsan, the chancellor.



    </string>
    <string name="buet_about">
        Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (Bengali: বাংলাদেশ প্রকৌশল বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়়, [baŋladeʃ prokowʃɔl biʃʃobiddalɔe̯]), commonly known as BUET(pronounced [bue̯eʈ]; Bengali: বুয়েট), is a public university in Bangladesh, which focuses on the study of engineering and architecture.[2] Founded in 1912, it is the oldest institution for the study of engineering, architecture and urban planning in Bangladesh.[3]
Every year, around 1055 students get accepted to their undergraduate programs to study engineering, architecture, and urban planning. Of the 10,000 candidates selected to write the undergraduate admission test from an initial application pool of over 10,000 applicants, only about the top 10% are admitted. Around 1000 graduate students are accepted into their Masters and PhD programmes on an annual basis. The total number of teachers is around 600. With the construction of new academic buildings, an auditorium complex, and halls of residence, the university has continued to expand over the last three decades. BUET has been ranked 135th among the Asian universitiesin the 2018 edition of QS World University Rankings


    </string>

    <string name="ru_about">
        The University of Rajshahi, also known as Rajshahi University or RU (Bengali: রাজশাহী বিশ্ববিদ্যালয় Rājshāhi Bish-shobid-daloy) is a public university which is the second largest university in Bangladesh, in Rajshahi, a city in northwestern Bangladesh. It was established in 1953, the second university to be established in what was then East Pakistan. The university is ranked third on the Bangladesh University Ranking 2017.[3]
The university 59 departments are organised into ten faculties. Rajshahi University is in a 753 acres (3 km2) campus in Motihar, 3 kilometres (2 mi) from the Rajshahi city centre. With 25,000 students and close to 1000 academic staff, it is one of the largest universities in Bangladesh.[4] In addition to hosting programs in engineering, arts, law, sciences, agriculture, social sciences, business studies and medical sciences, the university houses institutes of higher studies


    </string>

    <string name="ku_about">
        Khulna University (Bengali: খুলনা বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়) is a public university in Bangladesh.[3] It is situated at Gollamari, Khulna, Bangladesh, by the river Moyur, beside the Khulna-Satkhira highway. The academic programs of Khulna University started on 31 August 1991 with 80 students in four disciplines.[4] Khulna University has 28 disciplines under six schools and one institute. It is the only university in Bangladesh where student politics is not allowed. Students passing the Higher Secondary Certificate examination are very much interested in their admission in Khulna University for this politics-free environment. Khulna is an administrative division as well as the third largest metropolitan city in Bangladesh. The Mongla Sea Port, the Shipyard, the Bangladesh Naval Base are in Khulna. Khulna is an industrial city and famous for the Sundarbans.

    </string>

    <string name="ruet_about">
         Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology, commonly known as RUET (রুয়েট), is one of the leading PhD granting public research universities in Bangladesh. It is one of the
        five prestigious public universities in the country that specialises in the field of engineering. Just like the other public engineering universities, the admission battle of RUETis considered to be the toughest one in the country.[3]
RUET was founded in 1964 as Rajshahi Engineering College with a limited number of students. It was then changed to Bangladesh Institute of Technology (BIT) in 1986 and was finally renamed
        Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology (RUET) in 2003 when it gained a university status.
At present, more than 3500 students are pursuing their higher study in this green campus including under-graduate and post-graduate with
        over 250 prominent faculty members in diverse field of expertise. The medium of instruction and necessary assessment of this university is English


    </string>

    <string name="kuet_about">
        . Khulna University of Engineering and Technology (Bengali: খুলনা প্রকৌশল ও প্রযুক্তি বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়, pronounced [kʰulna prokouʃɔl o prodʒukti biʃːobiddalɔe̯])
        commonly known as KUET ([kue̯ʈ]; Bengali: কুয়েট), formerly BIT, Khulna, is a public engineering university of Bangladesh emphasizing education and
        research on engineering and technology. This is a renowned university for the study of engineering in Khulna, Bangladesh.

    </string>
</resources>
